## **Muhammed Esat Ozen**

#### **Software Developer**

Winchester, MA (203) 278-6572

ozenesat@gmail.com

Portfolio /, GitHub /, LinkedIn /

(Authorized to work in the US for any employer)

#### Skills

JavaScript, TypeScript, React, React-Native, Redux, Next.js, Node.js, Python, Adobe DTM, HTML5, CSS3, Ruby on Rails, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, Postman, REST, JSON, Git/GitHub/Gitlab, jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Phabricator, Ubuntu, Safe Agile, Kanban.

# **Experience**

JAN 2021 - PRESENT

### CVS Health, Woonsocket, RI- Software Engineer

- Developing web screens and components with React Native & TypeScript from scratch.
- Implementing Adobe Dynamic Tagging which increases the trackability and performance.
- Reviving and testing active PRs and mentoring the new members' onboarding process.
- Doing demos and attending daily standup, retro meetings under Safe Kanban disciplines.

MAY 2020 - DEC 2020

### Liana Networks, Beaverton, OR - Front-end Developer

- Designed, implemented and tested the application from scratch with Next.Js & React.
- Implemented OAuth 2.0 authorization to access Google APIs into the React app with JWT.
- Integrated YouTube Data API that hits ~10 K req. per day for the live stream and live chat.
- Developed the start & control live broadcast functionality with YouTube Live Streaming
  API which reduced the onboarding time by half and improved product usability.
- Built and consumed Restful APIs in coordination with 3rd Party APIs & SDKs and backend.

# **Featured Start-up Projects**

- <u>Earnie:</u> Start-up project based on an AI for stock market which allows user's to create and run strategies on Stock Market with Alpaca. {React, Redux, AWS, Python, JS, OAuth, REST}
- QMic: Start-up project which allows live broadcasts to get online guests with `n to 1` communication principle. {React, Redux, Python, PostgreSQL, OAuth, Phabricator, REST}
- <u>Rapic</u>: Start-up project which allows front-end developers to manage their back-end database services over a web page. {React, Next.js, Python, PostgreSQL, GitLab, REST}

# **Other Experience**

MAY 2019 - FEB 2020

### Ace It Education, Boston, MA - Web Developer

- Built and maintained two websites for the company's DBAs with WordPress.
- Managed e-mail accounts with G-Suite and e-mail campaigns with MailChimp.
- Provided technical support for the weekly events and classes of the company.
- Created social media and website content. Advertised the events via Eventbrite.

MAY 2018 - MAY 2019

## **The Fix, Farmington, CT** – *Project Manager*

- Efficiently managed a yearly budget of ~\$1 million and increased the profitability of the company by 10% with user and market research.
- Worked on improving sales strategies and customer satisfaction. Established the use of alternative products and services tailored to customer needs.

MAY 2013 - APR 2016

## Zaman Media Group, Ankara, Turkey – Correspondent

 Worked with editors and senior correspondents as a team to cover all of the latest political news from the Capitol. Reported on judicial news from the courts.

#### Education

FEB 2020 - MAY 2020

#### General Assembly, Boston, MA - Software Engineering Immersive

- Completed 12 weeks/500+ hours of intensive Full Stack Development instruction.
- Built client-side applications with responsive behavior using React with third-party APIs.
- Developed 4 full-stack web applications in four days sprints independently and collaboratively while practicing Agile methodology. Utilized Git for version control.

SEP 2008 - JUN 2012

# Middle East Technical University – Bachelor of Science, Mathematics

Abstract Algebra, Combinatorics, Cryptography, Discrete Mathematics, Intro. to C, Number Theory *Honors;* Proudly served as elected President of the Student Council for two years.

## Summary

With a quantitative academic background and startup experience, able to master new skills quickly. Enjoys breaking down and solving complex problems with analytical thinking in transferring innovative ideas into the codebase. Believes in team play and never-ending personal growth. Experienced in diverse work areas in three different countries as a highly adaptive world citizen.